Citizenfour is a documentary film directed by Laura Poitras.
In June 2013, Laura Poitras and reporter Glenn Greenwald flew to Hong
Kong for the first of many meetings with Edward Snowden.
She brought her camera with her.
Self, played by Edward Snowden.
Self, played by Glenn Greenwald.
Self, played by Laura Poitras.
Self, played by William Binney.
Self, played by Barack Obama.
Self, played by Jacob Appelbaum.
Citizenfour is a 2014 documentary film directed by Laura Poitras,
concerning Edward Snowden and the NSA spying scandal.
The film had its US premiere on October 10, 2014, at the New York Film Festival and
its UK premiere on October 17, 2014, at the BFI London Film Festival.
The film features Snowden and Glenn Greenwald, and was co-produced by Poitras, Mathilde Bonnefoy,
and Dirk Wilutzky, with Steven Soderbergh and others serving as executive producers.
Citizenfour received critical acclaim upon release, and was the recipient of numerous
accolades, including Best Documentary Feature at the 87th Academy Awards.
This film is the third part to a 9/11 trilogy following My
Country, My Country (2006) and The Oath (2010).
The film explores themes of biography, national security agency (nsa),
woman director, investigative journalism, whistleblower.